A Guide to the Constituent Correspondence: Mass Mailings of Governor Robert McDonnell, 2009-2013 (Bulk 2010-2013)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Constituent Correspondence: Mass Mailings of Governor Robert McDonnell, 2009-2013 2010-2013
The Library of Virginia
51120
7 cu. ft. (7 boxes)
Governor Robert McDonnell
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 51120 was transferred by Gov. Robert McDonnell, January 7, 2014.
Appraisal
This collection has been weeded for duplicates and non-records.
Biographical Information
Robert F. McDonnell was elected 71st governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia in November 2009 and inaugurated on 16 January 2010. He served until 11 January 2014.
The Office of Constituent Affairs was first established in 1984 to serve as a liaison between the Governor and the citizens of the Commonwealth. The Office oversees and coordinates responses to all mail sent to the Governor's Office. Constituent Affairs staff determine where and under whose signature the responses should be drafted and direct correspondence to the appropriate person in the administration. The Office also answers phone inquiries from constituents and occasionally meets with constituents to resolve problems and handle requests.
Scope and Content
Constituent Correspondence: Mass Mailings 2010-2013 is housed in 7 boxes and consists of letters received by Governor McDonnell from citizens, public officials, and various organizations.
Continuing from the previous administration, the Office of Constituent Services used IQ to track correspondence. The first three boxes in this collection are organized based on the IQ number, and is mostly chronological.
Samplings of the mass mailings include letters, postcards, and petitions relating to a variety of subjects such as: climate change, immigration enforcement, gay rights, proposed legislation, state funding and budget cuts, medicaide and medicare, the Affordable Care Act, gun rights, Confederate History Month, Planned Parenthood and abortion rights, offshore oil drilling, mental health services, stays of execution and petitions for clemency, E-Verify, "Last In First Out" in Virginia, Thank You Cards, Certificates of Recognition, general letters of complaint, uranium mining, transportation funding and proposals, among other issues.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by IQ number or chronologically, maintaining original arrangement when possible. Records are also arranged by topic when clear chronology was not possible.
Contents List
- Mass Mailings, 2010-2013., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 1-7)
  - 2010 Jan-Mar. (Box 1)
    - 2023100. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 2023300. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2023400. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 2023500. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 2039700. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 2022900. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 2019900. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 2020700. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 2020600. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 2020500. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 2020400. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 2020300. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 2020200. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 2020100. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 2018810. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 2018700. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 2018400. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 2010 Feb-June. (Box 2)
    - 2002900. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 2002800. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 2002700. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 2001800. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 2001700. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 2001400. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 2001900. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 2002100. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 2002400. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 2002600. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 2022800. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 2022700. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 2022600. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 2022500. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 202200. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 2022100. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 2021900. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 2021800. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 2021700. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 2021600. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 2010 May-Oct. (Box 3)
    - 2021500. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 2021400. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 2021200. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 2001100. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 2000900. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 2000800. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 2000700. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 2000600. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 2000500. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 2000400. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 2000300. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 2000350. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 2000200. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 2000100. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 2010 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 15-19)
    - 2010 Sept-Oct. (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - 2010 Oct-2011 Feb. (Box 4)
    - 2010 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - 2010 Oct-Dec. (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - 2010 Nov. (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - 2010 Nov-2011 Feb. (Box 4, Folder 9-13)
    - 2010 Dec. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - 2010 Dec-2011 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - 2011 Feb. (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - 2009-2012 (bulk 2011-2012). (Box 5)
    - 2011 Feb. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2011 Feb-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 2011 Mar. (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - 2011 Apr. (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - 2011 May. (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
    - 2011 June. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Trans-Vaginal Probe Petition 2011 Oct-Nov. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Women's Rights 484/462 2011 Oct-2012 Sept. (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
    - I Support Prayer Petition 2012 Jan-Feb. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 2009-2012. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - 2009-2010. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - 2010. (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
    - 2010-2012. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Certificates of Recognition 2010-2012. (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - 2011-2013. (Box 6)
    - Keystone XL Pipeline 2011. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - National Primary Care Week 2011. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Executions 2011. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Prayer 2011. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - POTUS Birth Certificate 2011-2012. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Bypass 2011-2012. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Healthcare 2011-2012. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - HB 189 2011-2012. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous 2011-2013. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Uranium Mining 2011-2013. (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - SB 597 2012. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - SB 598 2012 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Stand Your Ground 2012. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Neli Latson 2012. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Gun Rights 2012-2013. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Healthcare Exchange 2012-2013. (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - Transportation Legislation 2012-2013. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Redistricting and Voting Bills 2013. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Medicaid 2013 Jan-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 2011-2013. (Box 7)
    - Abortion 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Budget and Taxes 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Criminal Justice, Prison Reform, Restoration of Rights 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Environment 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - HB 1160, NDAA 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Headstart 2011. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Health and Healthcare 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    - Immigration 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
    - Old Dominion University Budget 2011 Sept. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - TAG, Education 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Transportation 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - ALEC 2012. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Voting 2011-2013. (Box 7, Folder 17)